<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><question_set><set_info author="bryan kennedy" title="Vaccination" num_easy="7" num_hard="7" date="Monday, February 22, 2010 - 11:50am"/><easy><question><question_txt>How does a vaccine work?</question_txt><answer_a>It poisons the viruses and bacteria in your body</answer_a><answer_b>It's like a prep course for your immune system</answer_b><answer_c>It doesn’t actually do anything</answer_c><explanation_txt>Vaccines contain materials that your body can use to “learn” how to fight infections. When an actual infection comes, your immune system already has defenses prepared against it, and you’ve got a head start in fighting the disease!</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>What does the “MMR” in “MMR vaccine” stand for?</question_txt><answer_a>Mister ManageR</answer_a><answer_b>Malignant Mitochondrial Repressor</answer_b><answer_c>Measles, Mumps and Rubella</answer_c><explanation_txt>The MMR vaccine contains weakened, or “attenuated,” samples of the viruses that cause the diseases measles, mumps and rubella. These three diseases can cause permanent damage to the body or even death, but after receiving the MMR vaccine at an early age, a person will be protected from them for life.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>What disease causes fevers, headaches, and a characteristic swelling in the cheeks and neck?</question_txt><answer_a>Measles</answer_a><answer_b>Mumps</answer_b><answer_c>Rubella</answer_c><explanation_txt>Mumps. The mumps virus often causes painful swelling in the salivary glands, resulting in swollen, puffy cheeks. In severe cases, a mumps infection can result in male sterility or death. The MMR vaccine protects you from ever getting it.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question><question><question_txt>What’s the name of the highly contagious disease famous for the spotty rash it causes?</question_txt><answer_a>Measles</answer_a><answer_b>Mumps</answer_b><answer_c>Rubella</answer_c><explanation_txt>Measles is an infection of the respiratory system (your lungs, nose and throat) that usually causes a red, spotty rash all over the body and can, in serious cases, cause pneumonia, encephalitis, blindness and death. An early dose of the MMR vaccine can ensure that you never develop measles.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>What disease with flu-like symptoms can pass from a pregnant mother to her baby, resulting in a dangerous congenital infection?</question_txt><answer_a>Measles</answer_a><answer_b>Mumps</answer_b><answer_c>Rubella</answer_c><explanation_txt>Rubella can cause flu-like symptoms and isn’t usually very dangerous. But if a pregnant mother becomes infected, the disease can result in a variety of severe health problems for the baby, or even cause miscarriage or stillbirth. Just like with measles and mumps, the MMR vaccine can provide lifelong protection from rubella.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>How long have people been using vaccines?</question_txt><answer_a>For hundreds of years</answer_a><answer_b>Since the 1940s</answer_b><answer_c>Since 1971</answer_c><explanation_txt>An English scientist named Edward Jenner is often credited with developing the first true vaccine in the late 1700s. But hundreds of years before that, even, people in Asia were protecting themselves from the smallpox virus through variolation, a process that relied on the same principles as vaccination.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>Influenza vaccines are often produced inside of…</question_txt><answer_a>Yogurt</answer_a><answer_b>Eggs</answer_b><answer_c>Oranges</answer_c><explanation_txt>Eggs. It may seem strange, but to make some flu vaccines, viruses are injected into raw chicken eggs. The viruses change so that they can reproduce inside the egg. When they are extracted from the egg they can no longer cause an infection in a person, but our immune systems can still use them to develop immunity to the original virus.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question></easy><hard><question><question_txt>Name the paralyzing and sometimes fatal disease stymied by vaccination in the 1950s.</question_txt><answer_a>Hansen’s disease (formerly known as leprosy)</answer_a><answer_b>Polio</answer_b><answer_c>Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease</answer_c><explanation_txt>Most active in the summer months, polio epidemics would leave thousands of people paralyzed and disfigured every year until widespread vaccinations in the ‘50s nearly eliminated the disease from North America.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question><question><question_txt>What virus causes smallpox, a disease responsible for millions of deaths from the time of the ancient Egyptians to the 18th century?</question_txt><answer_a>Variola major</answer_a><answer_b>Flavivirus (DENV)</answer_b><answer_c>Yersinia pestis</answer_c><explanation_txt>Variola viruses plagued humanity in the form of smallpox from pre-history until the development of a vaccine in the late 18th century. Even before the vaccine, some cultures found that resistance to the disease could be obtained by being exposed to viral material from an infected person. The process, called variolation, is more dangerous and less predictable than modern vaccination, but relies on the same principles.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>Smallpox is…</question_txt><answer_a>As dangerous as it ever was.</answer_a><answer_b>Mostly contained to states west of the Mississippi</answer_b><answer_c>Pretty much gone from the world.</answer_c><explanation_txt>Although the vaccine had been developed a century and a half earlier, smallpox persisted in small pockets around the world until the 1970s, when an intensive, global vaccination campaign finally erased the disease from the planet. Smallpox is the only human disease to have been completely eradicated.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>The smallpox vaccine was discovered thanks to…</question_txt><answer_a>Porcupine quills and sweaty zookeepers</answer_a><answer_b>Horse hooves and itchy jockeys</answer_b><answer_c>Cow udders and blistery milkmaids</answer_c><explanation_txt>Dairy cows can sometimes pass a disease called “cowpox” to humans. Back in the 1700s, doctors noticed that milkmaids who had contracted and recovered from cowpox became resistant to the much more dangerous smallpox. They realized that intentionally infecting someone with cowpox was a safe way to protect them from smallpox, an idea that has been highly refined in modern vaccines.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>The deadly, vaccine-preventable disease pertussis is also known as…</question_txt><answer_a>Tuberculosis</answer_a><answer_b>Whooping cough</answer_b><answer_c>Break-bone fever</answer_c><explanation_txt>Persussis is commonly known as “whooping cough” for the sometimes high-pitched coughing that is a symptom of the disease. The pertussis vaccine grants protection from infection for several years; it is usually given to children, whose age makes them most vulnerable to the disease.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question><question><question_txt>Without a vaccination, the fatality rate for a person infected with diphtheria is about…</question_txt><answer_a>1 in 10</answer_a><answer_b>1 in 50</answer_b><answer_c>1 in 100</answer_c><explanation_txt>Between 5% and 10% of those infected with diphtheria die from the disease. Although a vaccine for the deadly bacterial infection was developed in the 1920s, outbreaks still occasionally occur in areas with low vaccination rates.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>What does “herd immunity” refer to?</question_txt><answer_a>Disease protection due to immunity in a community</answer_a><answer_b>Disease protection due to life in large groups</answer_b><answer_c>Disease protection through close contact with cows</answer_c><explanation_txt>When lots of people in a group are vaccinated, the whole group gains protection from disease. This is referred to as “herd immunity.” But when too many people choose not to be vaccinated, it increases the chances of other people in the group getting sick.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question></hard></question_set>