<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><question_set><set_info author="JBack" title="What is snow?" num_easy="7" num_hard="7" date="Monday, February 22, 2010 - 12:33pm"/><easy><question><question_txt>What is snow?</question_txt><answer_a>Crystals of ice</answer_a><answer_b>Tiny pieces of clouds</answer_b><answer_c>Feathers from snow birds</answer_c><explanation_txt>Snow is simply molecules of frozen water--ice--in crystallized form. Most snow forms when water vapor in the air suddenly cools and turns directly into ice, a process called sublimation. In honor of the Minnesota winter, all the questions in this set deal with snow.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>How big can snowflakes get?</question_txt><answer_a>One inch across</answer_a><answer_b>Two inches across</answer_b><answer_c>Six inches across</answer_c><explanation_txt>Most snowflakes are less than half and inch across. But under the right conditions--high humidity, temperatures just below freezing, light winds, and lots of updrafts - flakes close to two inches across can form. (Of course, it's impossible to measure every single snowflake, so no one knows what the largest flake ever would be.)</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question><question><question_txt>Why is snow white?</question_txt><answer_a>Because that's what the dwarves named her</answer_a><answer_b>Because it reflects light</answer_b><answer_c>Because white dust is trapped inside</answer_c><explanation_txt>Sunlight contains light rays of many different frequencies. Most objects absorb some frequencies and reflect others. Our eyes perceive specific frequencies as specific colors. The complex surface of snow crystals scatters the light, mixing all the frequencies together. We see this mix of frequencies as white.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question><question><question_txt>Is it ever too cold to snow?</question_txt><answer_a>Yes</answer_a><answer_b>No</answer_b><answer_c></answer_c><explanation_txt>All you need for snow is water vapor and cold temperatures. Now, cold air holds less moisture than warm air, so when temperatures drop below 15 degrees, heavy snowfall becomes unlikely. (The South Pole, which has an average temperature of 4 below, gets less than an inch of snow a year.) But it is never too cold to snow.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question><question><question_txt>Does snow get fluffier as temperatures get colder?</question_txt><answer_a>Yes</answer_a><answer_b>No</answer_b><answer_c>Only to a point</answer_c><explanation_txt>When temperatures are just below freezing, snow tends to be heavy and wet. As temperatures drop, down to about 15 degrees, snow tends to get fluffier. But if it gets even colder, the structure of the snow crystals changes. Near 0 degrees Fahrenheit and below, the crystals tend to be smaller and thus pack together more tightly on the ground - making things decidedly less fluffy. Wind also plays a role. Strong winds break up large, fluffy snowflakes into smaller crystals that pack more densely.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>There is one inch of water in ten inches of snow:</question_txt><answer_a>True</answer_a><answer_b>False</answer_b><answer_c>True only under certain conditions</answer_c><explanation_txt>The famous ten-to-one ratio generally applies only to pretty dense snows - those near 32 degrees Fahrenheit or with heavy winds. Most US snowfalls are fluffier, with ten inches of snow holding only 4/10 of an inch of water.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>This contains the text that will be displayed within the quiz show.</question_txt><answer_a>Ice on the lake surface</answer_a><answer_b>The temperature difference between water and air</answer_b><answer_c>Elves</answer_c><explanation_txt>Lakes constantly lose water to evaporation, even in winter (as long as they don't freeze over). When a mass of very cold air moves across a lake, it can freeze the water vapor in the air, creating snow. All snowfall comes from freezing water vapor. In a "normal" snowfall, a low-pressure system sucks warm, moist air up from the south and lifts it high in the air until it freezes.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question></easy><hard><question><question_txt>True or false: snow is a good insulator:</question_txt><answer_a>True</answer_a><answer_b>False</answer_b><answer_c></answer_c><explanation_txt>Surprisingly, snow is very good at trapping heat. Piles of flakes trap small pockets of air － fresh, uncompacted snow is 90%-95% air. This air cannot move, so heat does not transfer quickly. An object buried in the snow will typically stay warmer than a similar object left exposed. (Of course, if the object is over 32 °, it will melt the insulating blanket of snow.)</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>How many snow storms hit the US in a typical year?</question_txt><answer_a>About 100</answer_a><answer_b>About 200</answer_b><answer_c>About 500</answer_c><explanation_txt>Each year an average of 105 snow-producing storms hit the continental United States. A typical storm will snow for two to five days.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>Snow has fallen on every part of the continental United States:</question_txt><answer_a>True</answer_a><answer_b>False</answer_b><answer_c></answer_c><explanation_txt>True. Pretty much every spot in the US (except Hawaii) has seen snow at some point. It even snowed in Miami, Florida on January 17, 1997.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>In the western US, melting snow from mountain tops contributes how much to the annual water supply?</question_txt><answer_a>Up to 25%</answer_a><answer_b>Up to 50%</answer_b><answer_c>Up to 75%</answer_c><explanation_txt>As warm, moist air flows in from the Pacific Ocean, it has to rise to get over the Rocky Mountains. As it rises, it gets colder, and the water vapor freezes into snow, which falls on the mountaintops. Therefore, once the air passes over the mountain, it has little water left. This means that, in the summer, some areas of the West get very little rain. But the snow which fell over the winter melts and runs down the mountains to form rivers.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>The snowiest place in the world is:</question_txt><answer_a>Mt. Rainier, Washington</answer_a><answer_b>Valdivostok, Siberia</answer_b><answer_c>The South Pole</answer_c><explanation_txt>Paradise Visitor Center at Mount Rainier National Park, about 90 miles south of Seattle, averages better than 56 feet of snow each year! Its worst winter was 1939-40, when it received a paltry 26 feet. In 1971-72, it set the all-time world's record of 93 feet, 6 inches! The South Pole, by contrast, gets less than an inch of snow each year. The Antarctic air is so cold, it holds very little moisture which can turn into snow.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>The snowiest city in the US is:</question_txt><answer_a>Rochester, New York</answer_a><answer_b>Duluth, Minnesota</answer_b><answer_c>Fairbanks, Alaska</answer_c><explanation_txt>Rochester receives an average of 94 inches of the white stuff each year. Duluth checks in at 80 inches. By comparison, the Twin Cities gets a paltry 50 inches a year (though it doesn't seem so paltry when you've got to shovel the driveway!)</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>Which side of a building forms the most icicles?</question_txt><answer_a>North</answer_a><answer_b>South</answer_b><answer_c>West</answer_c><explanation_txt>The south side of a building faces the low winter sun all day long. The sun slowly melts the snow on the roof. When the water starts to drip, it meets the cold air and freezes.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question></hard></question_set>