<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><question_set><set_info author="bryan kennedy" title="Winter phenology 09" num_easy="5" num_hard="5" date="Monday, February 22, 2010 - 11:21am"/><easy><question><question_txt>Which of these animals hibernates during the cold winter months?</question_txt><answer_a>The bird we call “nuthatch”</answer_a><answer_b>The creature we call “hedgehog”</answer_b><answer_c>The beast we call “black bear"</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: b) Hey… what was that snapping sound? It was the sound of you getting served! That’s right—bears don’t really enter into a state of “true hibernation.” Bears’ internal processes slow to conserve energy in the winter, but they are easily wakened, and their body temperatures drop only slightly. Many smaller mammals, like the hedgehog, are true hibernators, and their body temperatures and heart rates will drop significantly when they burrow in for the winter.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question><question><question_txt>The “aurora borealis”—what the heck is it?</question_txt><answer_a>A seasonal cold air mass from the high arctic</answer_a><answer_b>The most beautiful male figure skater in the world</answer_b><answer_c>The luminescent emanations of charged particles bl</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: c) I thought you’d get this one. “Aurora borealis” is another term for “northern lights.” The northern lights are caused by charged particles (like electrons) from the sun flying through space and colliding with gas molecules in Earth’s atmosphere. On clear winter nights you can sometimes see the light given off by these collisions in the northern sky.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>Why can’t you make good snowballs when it’s really, really cold out?</question_txt><answer_a>My fingers! They’re so cold and weak</answer_a><answer_b>It won’t snow if the weather is too cold.</answer_b><answer_c>All these snowflakes won’t melt!</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: c) To make a good snowball, you need it to melt just a little bit. When you squeeze snow together into a ball, some of the snowflakes melt. Everything freezes back together when you stop squeezing, making a nice, solid, snowball. When it’s too cold out, it’s hard to make that snow melt.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>Why do your teeth chatter so, my dear?</question_txt><answer_a>My face is trying to warm me up, I think.</answer_a><answer_b>I’m a only a little cold, but I’m very dramatic.</answer_b><answer_c>My nerves are spasmodic with hypothermia.</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: a) Teeth-chattering is just a symptom of shivering. When our bodies start to get too cold, our brain tells our muscles to contract and relax rapidly—shivering. These muscle contractions generate heat, warming us slightly.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>Dracula’s favorite night is:</question_txt><answer_a>December 21st</answer_a><answer_b>Oddly, Christmas</answer_b><answer_c>January 1st—no more blood this year!</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: a) Dracula’s favorite time of the year is right around December 21st and the winter solstice. The winter solstice is the day when the northern hemisphere is at its greatest angle away from the sun, meaning it has the shortest day and longest night of the year. A longer night means more time for Dracula to do whatever he wants: shop online, play videogames, or stalk his next victim.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question></easy><hard><question><question_txt>Ice is clear, snow is ice, snow is white. Why isn’t snow clear? Is this some kind of joke?</question_txt><answer_a>Nope: tiny dust particles in snowflakes keep them</answer_a><answer_b>Yeah, it actually is kind of a joke.</answer_b><answer_c>No, snowflakes are clear, but they get tricky in g</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: c) The ice snowflakes are made of is clear, but different spots on snowflake crystals will reflect different colors of light. When all these colors of light mix together, the reflected light becomes white, making the whole snowflake, or a mass of snowflakes, look white.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>Exactly what makes yellow snow yellow?</question_txt><answer_a>The widely available pigment “urochrome”.</answer_a><answer_b>Food coloring, and pranksters with free time.</answer_b><answer_c>Used Mountain Dew.</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: a) We all know what makes snow yellow, but what makes… that stuff yellow? The pigment urochrome, a product of broken down hemoglobin (a component of our blood), gives urine (and snow) its yellow color.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer A</correct></question><question><question_txt>What is “black ice”?</question_txt><answer_a>A figment of your imagination.</answer_a><answer_b>Frozen seepage from asphalt.</answer_b><answer_c>Clear ice.</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: c) “Black ice” is really just ice that forms free of air bubbles, making it very clear. Black ice forming on pavement can look black because of the surface beneath it, and can make for dangerous driving conditions.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer C</correct></question><question><question_txt>How do white-tailed deer keep warm in the winter?</question_txt><answer_a>Their winter diet includes warm meat—mice pulled f</answer_a><answer_b>Their winter coats are made of hollow hairs.</answer_b><answer_c>They maintain physical contact with other deer at</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: b) White-tailed deer grow winter coats with thousands of thick, hollow hairs. These hairs trap air, like the puffy filling of a winter coat, and insulate the deer from cold weather.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question><question><question_txt>Tell me about frostbite</question_txt><answer_a>Jack Frost nips at your nose, gangrene follows.</answer_a><answer_b>Blood vessels near the skin constrict, gangrene fo</answer_b><answer_c>Frozen muscles contract and split the skin, gangre</answer_c><explanation_txt>Answer: b) Frostbite starts when blood vessels near the skin begin to narrow to conserve heat in your body’s core. If blood flow is reduced by too much, tissue can begin to suffer from lack of oxygen. Extremities will eventually turn black and become blistered. Badly frostbitten tissue is usually removed, or it can become gangrenous.</explanation_txt><correct>Answer B</correct></question></hard></question_set>