<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><newscast><title><![CDATA[<p class="title">The 4-1-1 on lightning danger</p>]]></title><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Welcome to Science Buzz Weather, where we’ve always got our eyes on the skies. I’m ______________ and joining me today is lightning expert ______________________. What do you have to share with us today?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">EXPERT</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">This might seem obvious, but most people don’t think lightning will ever strike them. Yet last year there were 47 reported lightning deaths and 246 reported injuries. And a lot of lightning strikes don’t get reported.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">So what are a person’s statistical probabilities for getting struck by lightning?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">EXPERT</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">If you live a healthy life to age 80, your chances of getting hit by lightning at least once are 1 in 5,000. That’s far more likely than buying a winning lottery ticket.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">And not nearly as much fun! What can someone do to lower his or her chances of being hit by lightning?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">EXPERT</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Spend most of your time living in caves! Just kidding. Actually, there are some very simple measures you can take to avoid lightning strikes.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Such as?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">EXPERT</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">First, understand the weather patterns where you live. When thunderstorms are brewing, go inside. Second, when you’re inside, stay away from windows and open doors. Also avoid electrical lines and appliances or plumbing. They’re great conductors for lightning.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Any other tips?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">EXPERT</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Stay off the traditional land-line phone, since phone lines also conduct lightning well. Cell phones are a lot safer, but don’t get distracted from the weather while talking on one.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Why is lightning so dangerous, anyway?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">EXPERT</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Most people think a lighting strike causes a burn injury, like fire. But the electricity surging through your brain and body causes a nervous system injury instead. It can cause lasting damage like memory loss, depression, or paralysis.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Wow, that’s pretty intense. Thanks for all that good information, _____________. I’m  _____________ signing off from Science Buzz Weather.</p>]]></passage></actor><endline><![CDATA[<p class="footer">-- End of story --</p>]]></endline></newscast>