<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><newscast><title><![CDATA[<p class="title">The truth on forest fires with Smokey the Bear</p>]]></title><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Hello, I’m ________________, and welcome to this special edition of Science Buzz 60 Minutes. Tonight we have an unprecedented interview with Smokey the Bear, who’s ready to come clean with the truth on forest fires.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">SMOKEY</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Thank you for having me on the program tonight, ____________. There are a few things I want to get off my chest. In the past I might have been over-reacting a bit about all the dangers of forest fires.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">What do you mean, Smokey? Aren’t forest fires always bad?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">SMOKEY</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Let me be clear about this; we still need to be responsible campers and hikers when we’re outdoors. We don’t want to carelessly start forest fires. They can have a devastating impact on forests and people’s property.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">So what’s new?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">SMOKEY</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">People need to know that forest fires that occur naturally are a part of the re-growth cycle.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">You’re saying that forests need fires?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">SMOKEY</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">When a lightning strike starts a fire in the woods, the ensuing flames and heat burst the cones of pine-type trees and release millions of seeds onto the forest ground. That’s how old trees are naturally culled and new trees begin to grow. Within 30 or 40 years, some of those seeds have grown back into full-size trees.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Anything else you want to tell us about forest fires, Smokey?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">SMOKEY</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Yes, this process should happen around every 100 years to get new trees to grow. But remember, be careful with your campfires, kids.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Thanks for that great information Smokey. This is _________, signing off from Science Buzz 60 Minutes. Be sure to watch our show next week when Woody Woodpecker confesses to the damage his species causes trees.</p>]]></passage></actor><endline><![CDATA[<p class="footer">-- End of story --</p>]]></endline></newscast>