<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><newscast><title><![CDATA[<p class="title">Think twice</p>]]></title><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Good evening, St. Paul. I’m _____.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">And I’m _____. Welcome to a very special “Think Twice” edition of Science Buzz News.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">On “Think Twice” my co-anchor and I encourage each other to call “think twice” on statements that require a little extra reflection.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Think twice my friend! You are MY co-anchor! I’m the anchor, you’re the co-anchor.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">No, you think twice. Look at the teleprompter; I’m “Host 1.”</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Touché.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Item number one tonight; Famous former NASA astronaut Edgar Mitchell announces that the Roswell alien crash is real and the government has covered it up. American hero reveals far-reaching conspiracy! What do you think of that?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">I’m afraid we have to think twice here, Anchor. Captain Mitchell, the 6th man on the moon, is no doubt an American hero. But even heroes can be a little unbalanced at times. Just look at the Founding Fathers. Or Mike Tyson.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">You would consider Mike Tyson an American hero?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">I heard that they measured his punches at 1800 pounds per square inch.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Fair enough. I don’t think that’s a real measurement, but fair enough.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Item number two; Indiana Jones was a horrible archaeologist, but this doesn’t matter, because he carried a bullwhip.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">…</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">No “think twice”?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">No, I agree with you. What Indiana Jones does is treasure-hunting, not the meticulous science of archaeology… but that whip is pretty cool. Moving on—item number 3; air pollution is good for life on Earth.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Think twice! Air pollution caused by humans has vastly increased the levels of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere. This greenhouse gas is causing the temperature of the planet to rise at a rate to fast for many organisms to adapt to. Air pollution is causing global warming, plain and simple.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Think twice back at you. Not all human pollution consists of greenhouse gases. Some air pollutants have the effect of actually blocking solar energy, a phenomenon called “global dimming.” This shading of the planet, as unnatural as it is, may actually be helping keep Earth cool.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Think twice, think twice. If “global dimming” actually does affect global temperatures, it’s only delaying climate change. The source of the problem is unaffected by the global dimming.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Think, my friend, and then think again. New research suggests that air pollution causes sunlight to be scattered more effectively in the atmosphere. So while less light may be reaching plants on the ground, the scattered light means that more leaves are receiving light. When leaves are exposed to sunlight, they perform photosynthesis. A photosynthesizing plant is a growing plant, and plants suck carbon dioxide from the atmosphere to grow. Since the 1960s, air pollution has caused plants across the planet to become more productive, which has helped reduce the amount of carbon dioxide released into the atmosphere by humans.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Whoa.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Yeah.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">But… Air pollution is still bad for you, right? And it’s only slowing global warming a little, not stopping it, right?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">… Yes.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 2</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">We all lose! But I win!</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST 1</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Until next time, everybody, thanks for watching Science Buzz News.</p>]]></passage></actor><endline><![CDATA[<p class="footer">-- End of story --</p>]]></endline></newscast>