<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><newscast><title><![CDATA[<p class="title">What's the cost of water?</p>]]></title><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Welcome to Science Buzz Consumer Action. I’m __________, and today’s topic is the price we pay for bottled water versus tap water. Joining me today is noted hydrologist _____________. So what’s the big deal with water?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HYDROLOGIST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">It’s no secret that bottled water has become very popular these days. What we’re asking is if it’s really the right, and cheapest, way to keep yourself hydrated.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Well, bottled water is certainly cheaper than soft drinks, isn’t it?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HYDROLOGIST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">That’s true, but we usually don’t make comparisons with the cost of drinking the same amount of tap water. If you drink the recommended eight glasses of water a day from your tap, the typical municipal water cost is about 49 cents per year. Buying the same volume of water in bottles costs about 1,400 dollars per year.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Wow. That’s a huge difference. But of course bottled water tastes a lot better than tap water, right?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HYDROLOGIST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Wrong. In most blind taste tests that have been done, a consistent majority of sippers have preferred tap water to bottled waters.</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">But isn’t bottled water safer than tap water?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HYDROLOGIST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Well, we’re not sure. Companies that bottle water don’t have to publish their water testing results. But city water plants do. Plus, most city water works also add fluoride to their water to help prevent tooth decay. And there’s the environmental factor to consider; what happens to all the plastic bottles that get thrown away?</p>]]></passage></actor><actor><name><![CDATA[<p class="actor1">HOST</p>]]></name><passage><![CDATA[<p class="story">Amazing. I think I’m starting to see the bottled water/tap water issue a lot more clearly now. Thanks for your sharing your insights, ___________.</p>]]></passage></actor><endline><![CDATA[<p class="footer">-- End of story --</p>]]></endline></newscast>