<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comments>
	<selected_items>
		<item>
			<name>Chainsaw</name>
			<comment>The chainsaw was a poor choice, amateur archaeologist. It destroyed your dig site.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Shaker screen</name>
			<comment>The shaker screen will be a great help in finding little artifacts in the sand and dirt.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Trowel</name>
			<comment>A trowel is an excellent choice. Archaeologists live and die by the success of their troweling.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Tire buckets</name>
			<comment>Tire buckets aren’t the best-looking tools, but they’re incredibly handy at a work site.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Dynamite</name>
			<comment>Dynamite? Are you nuts? You just blew up all the artifacts!</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Blow dryer</name>
			<comment>A blow dryer might make you the best-looking archaeologist in Egypt, but it’s not going to find much for you.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Gophers</name>
			<comment>Gophers aren’t native to Egypt. You risk ruining the natural environment. Plus, the little fellers are really hard to train.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Camera</name>
			<comment>A camera is a good choice. You’ll want to record things just as you found them.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Laptop computer</name>
			<comment>Laptop computers are essential nowadays. Make sure you keep the blowing sand from getting into the keyboard.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Air conditioner</name>
			<comment>An air conditioner will suck all the juice out of the generator. There are cheaper, easier ways to keep cool.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Television</name>
			<comment>TV is a waste of good digging time. Digging season is short—you need to make every minute count.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>DVD player</name>
			<comment>Leave the DVD player at home. You’ll be too busy working. Besides,  Netflix and Blockbuster don’t reach the remote areas of Egypt.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Generator</name>
			<comment>A generator is a good investment for a successful mission. You’re going to need electricity to power your computers and other gear.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Sand bags</name>
			<comment>Sand bags can help keep your dig walls from collapsing.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Flip-flops</name>
			<comment>Flip-flops are a bad choice. Working on an archaeology dig is not a day at the beach.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Hamburgers</name>
			<comment>Hamburgers are a poor food choice. A lot of that meat is going to spoil in the heat.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Macaroni</name>
			<comment>Macaroni is a good selection. You can get a lot of food out of macaroni just by boiling it in water.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Hot dogs</name>
			<comment>Hot dogs will spoil long before you’re done with your dig.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Ice cream</name>
			<comment>Hey Einstein, ice cream is not going to last too long in the desert. Try picking some food that’s going to hold up in the heat.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Instant mashed potatoes</name>
			<comment>Instant mashed potatoes are a good selection. Dry foods keep well in the desert.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Pizza</name>
			<comment>Pizza might be tasty, but the ingredients won’t last long in the dry desert air.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Soup</name>
			<comment>Soup is a good food choice. Just add water and you’ve got a full meal.</comment>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Shorts</name>
			<comment>Wearing shorts while digging will beat up your legs.</comment>
		</item>
	</selected_items>
</comments>