<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questions>
	<question>
		<text>
			How do you get to and from sites? Are any specific types of cars, trucks or land rovers used more than others? What other methods of transportation are used? Airplanes? Animals?
		</text>
		<answer1>
			Usually just any 4-wheel drive vehicle we can find.  Or sometimes any vehicle that is available. Sometimes, even a canoe.
		</answer1>
		<answer2>
			For desert surveys, we use 4x4 vehicles, preferably six-cylinder or larger. We also sometimes walk or use camels. Otherwise, we use conventional transportation like planes or cars.
		</answer2>
		<answer3>
			On the DOP project we have three very old land rovers -- they have definitely seen better days!
		</answer3>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>
			How do you transport the artifacts once you’ve dug them up? Where do they go?
		</text>
		<answer1>
			Artifacts are taken back to the lab by the researchers themselves. They never leave our control - if we can help it.
		</answer1>
		<answer2>
			We use our storage room, or those that belong to the Egyptian Supreme Council of Antiquities.
		</answer2>
		<answer3>
			The artifacts are transported by either the archaeologists or conservators (depending on the object). We have specially-made crates for fragile objects. Most objects go to our store room, or, if the inspector considers it "valuable," it may go to the Antiquities Service.
		</answer3>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>
			Are there any animals at the sites? Which ones? Are they used as some sort of labor, are they pets, or are they wild?
		</text>
		<answer1>
			Depending on the site, there may be wild pests, ticks, snakes, etc. (Once I was almost run over by a moose, but I suspect that's not a problem in Egypt.) Pets are strongly discouraged, but sometimes show up.
		</answer1>
		<answer2>
			We see some wild animals. And we find dead animal mummies. Sometimes donkeys are used to bring water.
		</answer2>
		<answer3>
			We have guard dogs and donkeys at our sites, both brought by site guards.
		</answer3>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>
			Do you use tents, shade structures, backpacks or other "outdoor" equipment?
		</text>
		<answer1>
			Yes, all of the above.
		</answer1>
		<answer2>
			Tents -- we would use any brand that will give us free stuff. So far, strangely, we have had few eager donors. Also, we use backpacks, solar-powered batteries, solar showers (very rare as water is scarce).
		</answer2>
		<answer3>
			At one of our sites we have added awnings onto buildings that are used as on-site labs and storage. At our other site, we use large canvas tents. I also use a backpack every day to carry my essential materials.
		</answer3>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>
			What portable equipment do you use at a dig?
		</text>
		<answer1>
			Hand tools -- trowels, metric tape measures, flat-bladed shovel, GPS.
		</answer1>
		<answer2>
			Macintosh computers, global positioning systems, trowels, hammers, nails, ropes, rope ladders (made-to-order in Egypt), Nokia Total Station, etc.
		</answer2>
		<answer3>
			We use transits for mapping, GPS units, screens, wheelbarrows, special digging hoes, muktuf (special baskets made from tires for hauling sand). I also have all my field equipment.
		</answer3>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>
			Do you use computers in the field? How do you keep them from getting covered in dust? What types of software do you use?
		</text>
		<answer1>
			Increasingly, we do use computers in the field. Computerized total stations and PCs. And they get dusty, in spite of strenuous efforts to keep them clean.
		</answer1>
		<answer2>
			We use Macintosh computers and keep them clean with hope, optimism and plastic bags. Software that we use includes Microsoft Word, Photoshop and data management stuff.
		</answer2>
		<answer3>
			We've also started using laptop computers in the field (and, like Salima, hope that they will survive the dust!). Sometimes we attempt to store them in large Ziplock bags. We use all sorts of software, but mostly Excel and Word.
		</answer3>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>
			Do you use cameras, video cameras or any other type of recording equipment? How is it used? What other methods do you use to document sites? Do you ever take visitors or tourists through a research site, or are only researchers allowed?
		</text>
		<answer1>
			Cameras -- digital these days. Video cameras -- sometimes, depending on circumstances. Visitors/tourists can visit a site, depending on security issues, but not in the actual dig area. They could step on something important and damage it, or fall in an open unit and hurt themselves.
		</answer1>
		<answer2>
			We use digital cameras now. We have also used digital cameras for aerial photos. Other methods we use to document sites include walking, drawing, GPS and surveying equipment.
		</answer2>
		<answer3>
			Yes, in addition to our maps, we document everything using cameras. We have recently moved everything to digital cameras. Since Dakhleh is a little remote, we do not see as many tourists as some sites. However we do occasionally have visitors, but many need permission to come on our sites. Some of the Dakhleh sites are now open to tourists.
		</answer3>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>
			Do you sleep at the site, or does everyone leave at the end of the day? Where do people stay?
		</text>
		<answer1>
			Depends on the situation. If security is an issue, you may sleep at the site. If not, a camp or, depending on the project, at a nearby hotel.
		</answer1>
		<answer2>
			Depends on the site.
		</answer2>
		<answer3>
			At Dakhleh we have our field headquarters or dighouse that was built away from the sites.  We commute a 15-20 minute drive to our site. We are very spoiled at this site from an archaeological perspective. The other site I work at, called Deir al-Barsha has the dig house built on the perimeter of the site so everyone can walk to their different dig locations each morning.
		</answer3>
	</question>
	<question>
		<text>
			If you had to pick the top 3 to 10 items that you always take with you into the field, what would they be?
		</text>
		<answer1>
			Hat, good boots, water, compass, camera, notebook with pencils, field pack (with basic hand tools -- trowel, tape measure, etc), cell phone (or satellite phone, depending on project). And, I agree completely with Salima, chocolate.
		</answer1>
		<answer2>
			Camera, pen and paper, scarf, boots or sandals, water container, tape measure, trowel, compass, backpack, satellite phone, computer and chocolate.
		</answer2>
		<answer3>
			Mosquito net (not necessarily for mosquitoes, but to keep strange things from falling on me while I sleep), camera, field equipment kit, sunscreen and sunglasses, hat, computer, creature comforts like shampoo, special foods (I always have a supply of teas, candy, etc.) and warm clothing (to battle cold desert mornings).
		</answer3>
	</question>
</questions>